Naoki!
いりえことこ (入江琴子)入江君!
Blow out the candles, Kotoko.
なおき (入江直樹) さあ琴子火消して
Okay.
うん
Hmm?
ん?
What?
あれ?
That's not right.
(琴子)おっかしいな
Good morning.
おはよう
Oh, morning.
あつおはよう
Doing facial exercises in your sleep?
寝ながら百面相の練習か?
What?
え?
First you were smiling. Then you puckered up like a fish.
ニマニマ笑ってると思ったら 急に
A fish?
ひょっとこ?
Oh...
あ~
It was a dream!
夢かあ~
Sigh...
ききょうもとき (桔梗幹) あたしこの前焼肉屋さんの店員 紹介したでしょ?
Why the exaggerated sigh?
しながわまりな (品川真里菜) 何よこれ見よがしな ため息なんかついちゃつて
I know you are all aware
みんなご存じだとは 思うけど
that the 28th of this month is my birthday.
私今月28日 誕生日なのよねえ
We had no clue.
知らないわよそんなの
Neither does Naoki. Probably.
そう入江君も 知らないのよねたぶん
What?! Why not?
(3人)えっ!! えつ
He's your husband!
夫婦なのに!?
He has 200 on IQ test, but not when it comes to birthdays...
そーなのよ10200なのに なんで覚えてくれないのかな
Not even in one corner of his brilliant mind?
そーよねその優秀な脳の 片隅にでも…ねえ
No room for trivia?
おぐらともこ (小倉智子)興味のないことは インプットされないのかしら
His mom throws me a party every year
かあ 毎年お義母さんが パーティー開いてくれて
and he's forced to attend.
無理やり参加させられてるけど
But I want him to want to celebrate my birthday!
自分から進んで 愛する妻の誕生日を祝おう!
But he has no interest...
っていう気持ちに 欠けてるのよね入江君
That's not love.
それは確かに愛がないわね
I wouldn't stand for it.
あたしだったら耐えられないわ こり
I'd be fine with a super expensive present.
あたしはたっか~いプレゼント こつ もらえればそれでいつかなあ
You're so materialistic.
(幹) ったくあんたは
Why don't you ask for a present?
琴子もプレゼントだけ もらえばいいじゃん
A super expensive one!
たっか~いの こつか~ おねだりしちゃいなさいよ!
It's not the price! A gift should be heartfelt.
値段じゃないわよ プレゼントは!
What has he given you so far?
で今まで どんなものもらったの?
What has he given me? Well...
あっどんなものって そりゃあ...
Tell us! Tell us!
知りたい知りたい!
Tell us what he gave you!
入江さんがどんなもの あげたのか興味ある~!
Hmm? Huh?
ん?あれ?
Wait a minute, he's never...
(琴子) まさか…私って一度も
He's never given me a present.
入江君からプレゼント もらったこと...ない?
No way!
(幹達)ウッソ~ !
How many years have you been married?
あんた達 何年一緒にいんのよ~!
I can't believe it.
信じらんない
Poor Kotoko.
琴子さんかわいそう
This calls for a divorce!
うーわ!離婚よ離婚!
He doesn't love you at all!
あんたそれ ちい~っとも愛されてないわよ
That's not true! He's just a little shy.
そんなことないわよ! 入江君はただ照れ屋なだけで…
I know he loves me.
決して愛されていないわけじゃ
Here is a problem.
問題ねこれ
Is there another woman?
他に女がいるかも
Fine!
わかったわよ!
This year, it will be roses, and champagne,
今年こそ年の数だけのバラの花束 シャンパンそして…
and a heartfelt present. I will make it come true!
愛のこもったプレゼント 実現してみせるわ!おー!
1000 yen that it doesn't.
無理な方に千円
Me, too. 1000 yen.
あたしも無理な方に千円
Count me in. 1000 yen.
私もダメに千円
Doesn't anyone have faith?
ちょっと~ 誰か大穴狙いなさいよ!
The 28th?
28日?
Yes!
うんうん!
I have surgery and night duty.
オペが入ってる夜は当直
Was there something else?
何かあったっけその日?
He doesn't remember...
(琴子) や...やっぱり覚えてないみたい
Never mind.
じゃあいいです~
I won't give up! This calls for...
(琴子) こんなことで へこたれないわよ!
There you are, Mr. Irie!
ふなっせいいち (船津誠一)いた!入江さん!
What's with you?
かとう (加藤)何だ騒々しいな
I'll take your shift on the 28th.
28日の当直 僕が代わって差し上げます
Huh?
は?
On the 28th.
だから28日は
I don't need to switch shifts.
俺は 代わってもらう必要はないけど
Huh?
えっ… えつ...
-But you have to! -Huh?
それは困ります!
You have to switch with me!
何としてでも 代わっていただかないと
Or else Kotoko-- Oops.
じゃないと琴子さんが…あっ
Why do I have to?
何が困るって?
No...
え…いえ
What did Kotoko tell you?
(直樹)琴子に何を言われた
No, nothing.
いやな…なつ何も よ…なつ1D
Funatsu!
船津!
Kotoko said if I switch shifts with you on the 28th
琴子さんが28日の当直 入江さんと代わってくれたら
she'll arrange a date for me with Miss Marina.
真里奈さんと僕を デートさせてくれるって
A date?
は?デート?
So, please let me take your shift on the 28th!
ですからぜひ28日の当直 僕にやらせてください!
That's a promise!
約束ですからね!
What's with Funatsu?
船津…何だあれ
Just you and Naoki?
のりこ (入江紀子) お兄ちゃんと二人っきりで?
I'm sorry...
え...すいません
I'm so sad!
え~寂しいわ~ !
I was looking forward to this event!
私今このイベントに かけてたのに~
The banner is almost finished.
垂れ幕だって こつ あと少しで完成だったのよ
Banner?
垂れ幕?
See?
ほら!
I'm sorry.
(琴子)のあっごめんなさい
We can have a party.
やっぱりいつも通りの パーティーに…お願い
No!
(紀子)いいえ!
You're absolutely right!
そうよ確かにそうだわ!
Naoki hates our parties.
今までお兄ちゃんは 我が家のパーティーに
He acts like he's forced to be there!
めんどくさそうな顔で 便乗してるだけだった!
I've never seen him give you a present.
プレゼントなんて 見た覚えがないわ
All right, Kotoko!
わかったわ琴子ちゃん!
You and Naoki should spend some quality time together this year.
今年はお兄ちゃんと二人で 濃密な誕生日を過ごしなさい
I'll swallow my tears this time.
今回私は涙をのむわ 寂しいけど
Mom...
お義母さん
Let's put up a plan for this, Kotoko!
そうと決まったら作戦よ! 琴子ちゃん!
Okay!
はい!
How can we drop subtle hints,
どうやったらさりげな~く お兄ちゃんに
so, Naoki will remember your birthday?
琴子ちゃんの誕生日を 認識させるか
Yes...
はい..
Subtle hints won't work.
さりげなくは無理だろ こつ
What?
(RST)
You were scheming with Funatsu today.
お前病院で船津に 変な裏工作しやがって
Funatsu... That big mouth!
(琴子) 船津…口軽いんだから!
So, your birthday is coming up.
確かにお前誕生日だったな
Mom gets excited every year.
毎年この時期 お袋張り切ってるもんな
But I have no interest in birthdays.
でも俺そういうの興味ないから
Naoki, you're terrible!
まあお兄ちゃんったら 最低な男ね!
You have no interest in your beloved wife's birthday?
愛する妻の誕生日に "興味ない"とは何ですが!
Do you want to celebrate your birthday that badly?
お前さあそこまでして 俺と誕生日祝いたいの?
It was my lifelong dream.
そりゃあずっと夢だったし.
I see...
ふーん...
What kind of birthday is your lifelong dream?
言ってみろよ お前がしたい誕生日ってやつ
Tell him, Kotoko!
そーよーってやんなさいよ =つ 琴子ちゃん!
I just...
ただ私は…
I would get all dressed up.
とびっきりの おしゃれをして~-
Naoki would give me a huge bouquet of roses.
入江君は私の年の数だけの バラの花束を抱えてて~
We'd have dinner.
ディナーして
The chef would bring us a cake.
シェフがケーキを ン工 運んできてくれて~
Everyone would sing "Happy Birthday" to me.
店中が私のために 誕生日を祝ってくれるの
We would sip champagne.
(琴子)で入江君と私は シャンパンを飲んで
And spend the evening together.
二人っきりの夜を
I see how important this is to you.
(直樹) お前の誕生日にかける情熱は よくわかったよ
Huh?
え?
I'll switch shifts with Funatsu on the 28th.
28日船津に 当直代わってもらう
Really?
ほ…ほ…本当!?
Are you sure?
い…いついいの?
Yeah. He can be a pest, too.
あああいつもうるさいしなあ
Yay!
やったー!!
You did it, Kotoko!
やったわね琴子ちゃん!
Yay! Naoki!
わー!入江くーん!
From the day I met Naoki
(琴子)入江君を知った日から こんな誕生日が訪れることを
I dreamed of a birthday like this.
どんなに夢見てきたことか
My birthday finally came.
琴子)そんなこんなで 誕生日当日を迎えました
Don't forget, Naoki!
(琴子) 入江君ちゃんと覚えてる?
7:00 p.m. at the Royal Hotel lobby!
ロイヤルホテルのラウンジに 7時だからね!
Yeah.
ああ
Remember, Naoki.
そーよお兄ちゃん
I gave up my party plan for Kotoko!
琴子ちゃんの誕生日 涙をのんで譲ったんですからね!
Yeah.
ああ
I don't need a bouquet of roses. It's okay.
入江君年の数だけの バラの花束なんていいからね
Yeah!
ああ!
I really don't! Not at all.
ホントにいらないから! 欲しくなんかないからね
Give me a break! Enough already!
いい加減にしてくれ毎日毎日! 耳にタコだ!
Poor Naoki.
ゆうき (入江裕樹) お兄ちゃんかわいそうに
A little...
しげき (入江重樹) うん…ちょっとな
See you.
じゃあ
"Hair Salon at 3:30 p.m." I'd better get ready, too.
さつ私も のんびりしてられない
Put on my beautiful dress
(琴子) 素敵なドレスに…
and get my hair done
美容院でセットして もらって
into a beautiful hair style.
素敵な髪に してもらって.
And my make-up, too.
奮発してメークも してもらって
This is a special day.
今日のこの日のために
I'm going all-out!
一番素敵な私に してもらうんだ
He may fall in love with me all over again!
入江君私に惚れ直したりして
Mom, her hair looks like a cockatoo.
(男の子) お母さんあのお姉ちゃん 頭がオウムみたい
Shh!
坶親) これシーツ
This is terrible!
(琴子)何これ
What is this hair style?
この頭 どうしてこんなことに…
Maybe I should do it over! But I don't have time.
他の美容院に! いやそんな時間全然ない-
Maybe it's not as bad as I think...
もしかして自分が思うより 案外イケてるのかも… ?
Why couldn't I tell him I didn't like it?
どうして気に入らないって 言えなかったんだろう
I'm so stupid.
私のバカ...
What's wrong?
(男性)おいどうした!
Are you okay?
(男性)大丈夫ですか!
She started wavering and she doubled over.
あつなんか急にフラフラして しゃがみこんじゃったんですよ
She collapsed and hit her head!
そのまま倒れて 頭打っちゃつたんです!
Are you okay?
(琴子)大丈夫ですか? 大丈夫ですか?
Let's put your head up a little, okay?
ちょっと頭持ち上げますね
Okay.
よいしょ
Does anyone have a handkerchief?
すいません誰か ハンカチ貸してもらえませんか?
Thank you.
ありがとうございます
Can you call an ambulance?
あなた!救急車 呼んでもらってもいいですか?
Sure!
あつはい
Okay.
はい
Can I borrow your bag?
あつあの…カバン...
-Sure. -Place it under her head.
琴子)頭の下に入れてください
Is she a nurse?
(女性) あの人看護師さんだったの? こつた
I thought she was a barmaid.
(女性) ホステスさんじゃなかったんだね よかったんに
The ambulance will be here soon.
(琴子) もう少しで救急車来ますからね
Can you say your name?
名前言えますか?
Does it hurt anywhere else?
他にどこか痛いところ ありませんか?
She's lucky you were a nurse.
(救急隊員) いやあでも看護師さんが いてくれて助かりました
I think it's anemia, but she was also bleeding...
貧血だとは思うんですけど 出血もあったので
Thank you very much.
(救急隊員) じゃありがとうございました
You did a great job.
(男性) いやああんたよくやったよ
Good job, lady.
(男性)ホント お姉さんよくやったよなあ
Terrific.
(男性)ああすごかった
Very cool.
かっこよかったよ
Not really...
いやあ...
Her bag...
あの…カバン...
Just leave it there.
(救急隊員) ああじゃあちょっと そこ置いてください
You can come with us.
(救急隊員)あつお友達は ここにお願いします
I was just passing by.
(琴子)えっちよ...私 ただの通りすがりで
She's not my friend...
友達なんかじゃないんです…
Let me out!
おーい出して…あ~ !
What should I do? I'm over two hours late.
(琴子)どうしよう もう2時間以上も遅れてる
Naoki may have already left.
入江君もう帰っちゃつたかも
Why today?
なんで今日に限ってこんな
Sorry, Naoki!
(琴子) 入江君!ごめんね!
Please wait...
お願いもう少し ..
...a little longer!
待ってて!
Ma'am.
(スタッフ)お客様
What happened to your dress?
失礼ですがそのお召し物は どうなさったのでしょうか?
Are you hurt?
おケガでもされたんでしょうか?
This is... Oh, no!
やつこれは…違うんです!
What should I do?
ヤダどうしよう私
Ma'am?
(スタッフ)お客様?
I can't see Naoki like this.
こんな格好で 入江君に会うなんて…
I was supposed to meet someone here.
(琴子) 私ここで待ち合わせしてて
But I'm already 3 hours late.
でももう3時間以上も 待たせちゃつてて
Shall I call him?
ではお呼び出し いたしましょうか?
It's my birthday.
誕生日なのに
I can't see Naoki like this.
こんな格好で 入江君に会うなんて…
Ma'am...
お客様…
It's my first birthday with him.
初めて入江君に お祝いしてもらうのに…
I can't see him like this!
こんな格好じゃ会えないですよね
Why not wait over there?
あのとりあえず あちらの方で
Did he go home already?
入江君 もう帰っちゃいましたかね
I have no idea, ma'am.
それにつきましては わかりかねますが
Naoki?
入江君?
I thought you were hurt.
お前が ケガしたかと思ったろーが
You scared me.
ったく驚かせやがって
Naoki!
(琴子)入江君!
I'm sorry I'm so late.
ごめんなさい 私遅くなっちゃつて... よつ
A lot happened and I couldn't get here...
いろいろあって...なかなか たどり着けなくって
I was going crazy.
気が狂いそうになって
I thought you'd already left.
TCD...
But I couldn't give up.
でも諦めきれなくって
I knew you'd get here today,
今日はお前が何があっても
even if you had to crawl all the way.
這いつくばってでも来るのは わかってたから
How could I leave?
帰るに帰れないだろ?
But you look a mess.
しっかしすごいいでたちだな
I know...
うん入江君
You can tell me about it later.
話は後でゆっくり聞くとして
I'm hungry.
腹減ったな
The restaurant is closed.
予約していた店は 閉まっちゃってるし はる
And the way you look...
その格好じゃあな
Hey, guy!
汝性) チョットソコノオ兄サーン! ヨツ
Hi!
ハアーイ!
You dropped your package.
コレアナタノ荷物デースネ ソコニ落チテマシタ テマン
Someone will steal it if you leave it there.
コンナトコニ置イトクト 置キ引キニ遭イマース
Here you go. Hold it.
サッ持ッテ持ッテ ハイオ兄サン持ッテ~ ! 寺
Oh, no!
オー大変!
I have to catch a plane back to my home country.
ソロソロ飛行機ノ時間デス 国ニ戻ラネバ
Good luck, you two!
オフタリトモオ幸セー~ !
See you!
シーユー!
How pretty.
(琴子) きれい~
A rose for every year.
本当に年の数だけバラがある
And there's cake. Let's eat it.
ねえケーキもあるよ~ 食べよう!
What was my mom thinking?
お袋の奴何考えてんだ
What am I going to do with this?
これどーしろって言うんだ
Mom...
お義母さん
I wonder if she was secretly waiting for me?
もしかしてこっそりずっと 待っててくれたのかな私のこと
Probably. With her video camera.
だろうなどうせ ビデオでも撮ってたんだろ
She has so much time on her hands.
ったく…暇な奴 つに
But I'm so happy.
でも私すごく嬉しい
I'm the luckiest wife in the world.
こんな幸せ者のお嫁さん 他にいないよね
Happy birthday, Kotoko.
誕生日おめでとう琴子
Naoki...
NIE...
What do you want for a present?
プレゼント何が欲しい?
Rea-- Really?
えっ?ほ…本当? えつ
What should I ask for?
えーどうしようかなあ~
Um... Well...
えーっとねええーと
I get it!
あつじゃあ...
I want to hear you say, "I love you."
入江君に“好きって 言ってほしいな
"I love you."
"好き"って...
I take it back! Let me think again!
やっぱり...やっぱり今のナシ! 考え直す
Um... Well... Let me see...
えーっとねえーとえーと ん…うーん…
I love you, Kotoko.
琴子好きだよ
Me, too...
私も...
I love you...
大好き
It's been a while since I met Naoki,
(琴子)入江君と出会って もう随分経つのに
but my heart still pounds.
どうしてこんなに ドキドキするんだろう
Why do I...?
(琴子)どうしてこんなに
Why do I love him so much?
入江君のことが好きなんだろう
Oh...
あっ...
I forgot.
いけね
Does Naoki
(琴子)入江君も
love me just as much as I do?
私のこと 好きでいてくれてるのかな?
He makes my heart pound every day.
私は今も入江君に 毎日ドキドキしてるけど-
Do I...
入江君も
...make his heart pound sometimes?
たまにはドキドキなんか してくれてるのかな?
I hope I do.
そうだといいなあ
What's with the creepy smile?
いきなり不気味に笑うなよ
I never get tired of looking at it!
だって~見ても見ても こつ 飽きないんだもん!
That was over 2 months ago!
もう2か月も前だろ? お兄ちゃんにもらったの
I know.
そうだけどぉ~
But I could stare at it forever.
まだまだずう~っと 見てたいの~
I guess it was worth it.
お兄ちゃんも プレゼントした甲斐があるわねぇ
It brings you so much joy.
こんなに喜んでもらえて
Thank you.
ありがとうございます
It's from Chris.
おつクリスからだ
Oh, my God! Look at this!
え~っ何これ~ ! すごい~ ! 何~
How lovely!
まあ素敵~ !
What is it?
どうした
Look!
(琴子)見て見てこれ~ !
Dear Naoki and Kotoko...
(クリスティーヌ·ロビンス) “拝啓直樹&琴子"-
We held our wedding at a castle resort.
"アタシ達別荘ノオ城デ 式ヲ挙ゲテシマブ、マシテン
We've been on honeymoon in England for a while.
“新婚旅行ヲ兼ネテシバラク イギリスニオリマス,,-
We'll be a couple to rival the two of you!
44直樹卜琴子ニ負ケヘン夫婦二 ナルツモリヤデ".
I'm so happy right now. Chris.
"79シラ今メッチャ 幸セデッセークリス, テツ
Chris must come from a rich family.
クリスって すごい家の子だったんだね
I guess...
だな.
It's beautiful.
でもすごくきれいだね~
Kinnosuke looks pretty good, too.
きんのすけ 金之助も意外と似合ってんな
They both look so happy.
幸せそう二人とも
Yuki?
裕樹?
I feel kind of feverish.
なんかさっきから ちょっと熱っぽくて
What?
ええ?
He does.
あらっホントだわ 小
Maybe I got it from Konomi. She's not well, either.
このみ 好美の奴具合悪そうだったから うつったかな
Why would you catch her cold?
何してうつったのかしらね~
What are you saying?
こつ琴子 お前何言ってんだ!
All right. Wait a minute.
はいはいちょっと待っててね
Here.
はい
We were still okay at this time.
(琴子) この時にはまだまだ みんな余裕があったのでした
Now everyone's...
ったくそろいもそろって つに
Breathe in.
(直樹)吸って
Breathe out.
吐いて-
Open your mouth.
口あけて
Your throat is all red.
ああ…のども赤くなってるな
Dad, you're next.
次親父
Thanks.
(重樹)お願いします
At the time, the hospital was in a state of chaos.
(琴子)その頃病院でも 大変なことになっていました-
Even more than yesterday,
昨日までよりもさらに
we were inundated with influenza patients.
大勢のインフルエンザと見られる 患者が押し寄せ
So many people...
こんなに…
Excuse me.
失礼します
Are you from the Surgical Unit?
(看護師) あなた外科からの応援の方?
Yes! I'm Kotoko Irie!
はい!外科から参りました 入江琴子です
I'm here to support you.
どうぞよろしくお願いします
Naoki!
入江君!
Kotoko.
琴子
What are you doing here?
なんでここに
The same thing as you.
お前と同じ理由
What a coincidence!
そうなのね~ なんて偶然なのかしら?
I guess they see us as the dynamic duo.
やっぱり私達って みんなに頼られる夫婦なのね~ !
"Us?"
"達"? 達"?
You're the equivalent of 100 doctors! We can do it!
入江君がいれば百人力よね 頑張ろーね!
I guess.
そうだな
I get to work with Naoki.
(琴子)入江君と 一緒に働けるなんて…-
I'm so lucky!
私って なんてツイてるんだろう~ たつつ~
Ms. Irie?
入江さん?
Stop daydreaming. Come here.
ボサッとしてないでこっち来て
Oh, yes.
あつはい
The days that followed were like a nightmare.
(琴子) それからというもの殺人的な スケジュールが続いたのでした
Makiko Yamada. Please wait outside Room 2.
やまだまきこ 山田真紀子さん2番の お部屋の前でお待ちください
Yes.
(山田真紀子)はーい
Are you Mrs. Yamada?
(琴子)山田さんですが?
Please wait over here.
こちらでお待ちください
I'm prescribing an inhalant.
吸入するタイプのお薬を 出しておきます
Please start using it immediately.
薬をもらったら なるべく早く吸入してください
Thank you.
(女性)ありがとうございました
Take care.
お大事にどうぞ
Yum!
ん~おいしい!
Coming!
はーい
Hello? Irie residence.
はい入江でございます
Oh, Kotoko.
ああ琴子ちゃん
Oh, my! How are you holding up?
まあ大変ね~ 大丈夫?琴子ちゃん
For both us and your patients, you've hardly gotten any sleep.
ここのところ私達の看病と仕事で ちゃんと寝てないでしよう?
We're fine over here.
ん?あ…ああ こっちは大丈夫よ
My fever is almost gone, thanks to you.
私も熱もすっかり下がったし 琴子ちゃんのおかげで…うん
Yes.
はい
Don't work too hard.
じゃくれぐれも無理しないでね
Okay.
うんはい…
All right.
はーい
I hope she's okay.
ホントに大丈夫かしら?
So, you can't go home, too?
(直樹) お前も帰れなくなったのか
Naoki!
(琴子)入江君!
You're still here, too?
入江君も残ってるの?
There's too much going on.
ああこの状況じゃな
I'm so happy!
はあ~ !嬉しいな~ !
Our shifts rarely overlap.
あんまり二人でってないもんね
How can you be happy?
(直樹) よく喜べるよな
I've always dreamed about this.
だって~ずっとこういうのに こつ 憧れてたんだも~ん
What?
何?
I've been wanting to ask you...
お前さ前から聞こうと 思ってたんだけどさ
Are you feeling okay?
身体おかしくないか?
What? Uh...
え?あ…うん
I'm a little tired.
まつちょっとは 疲れてはいるけど
Maybe a little feverish. But I'm fine.
そういえば ちょっと熱っぽいかな?
Are you eating?
メシ食べてるか?
I don't have much of an appetite. We've been so busy.
あああんまり食欲なくって なくつ バタバタしてたし…
But I'm fine.
でも大丈夫
I see.
そうか
Naoki! Were you super worried about me?
ヤダ入江君!私のこと すごくすごーく心配してたの?
Were you worried your beloved wife had influenza?
愛する妻がインフルエンザに かかつてないかって!
No--
いやそういう
Oh, Naoki!
ヤダもう!入江君ったら~
I'm so happy.
も~嬉しいなあ
I see you're fine.
元気なのはわかった
-What's wrong? -An emergency.
どうしました?
It hurts!
たかし (貴史)痛い…痛いよ~
You'll be fine!
(母親)大丈夫大丈夫よ
Doctor! My son is...
先生先生!子供が
What's wrong?
どうしました?
His bike ran through a glass door.
自転車でガラス戸に 突っ込んじゃったそうです つたそつ
The bleeding doesn't stop.
血が…血が止まらなくて
I've been applying pressure.
ずっとこうやって押さえて 来たんですけど
You should have called an ambulance.
そういう時はお母さん 救急車呼んでいいんですよ
But if I let go...
(母親)でも手離したら…
...of the blood. I couldn't even make a phone call.
血が...血が出てきちやうから 電話もできなくて
Come sit over here.
とにかくこっちに 座らせてくださいねっ-
Let go. Let me see the wound.
手離して 傷口診せてくださいね
I need light.
(直樹)ライト
Let me have the towel, Mom.
(琴子)お母さんタオルを こっちに渡してください
It'll be fine.
大丈夫ですからねっ
It's fine.
大丈夫ですよ
We have to remove the glass.
(直樹) まずはガラスの破片 取り除かないとな
This may hurt a bit, but hang in there.
少し痛むかもしれないけど 頑張れよボク
-Ow... It hurts... -Takashi!
貴史! 中
I'm sorry, Takashi! I wish I could help you.
貴史ごめんね! ママ助けてあげられなくて
Calm down, Mom!
お母さん落ち着いて!
Your son will get scared if you're not calm!
お母さんがしっかりしないと 貴史君が不安がりますよ
Let's encourage him together!
一緒に励ましてあげましょ! ねっ
Nurse...
看護師さん
Don't worry. When it comes to removing glass,
大丈夫!-
Dr. Irie is Number 1!
日本ーって人ですから!
-Right? -Yes.
ねつ a
Takashi...
(母親)貴史
Be brave, Takashi!
頑張って貴史!
You can do it, Takashi.
よし頑張れよ貴史君
Ow... It hurts!
いたっ…痛い こつ...
Come on, Takashi!
(母親)頑張れ貴史!
Just a little more, Takashi.
もうちょっとだからね貴史君
I'm sorry.
坶親) さっきはすみませんでした
I panicked. I'm so embarrassed.
私取り乱しちゃつて 恥ずかしいです
That's natural. It must've been shocking.
そんなの当たり前ですよ ビックリしますよね
When you told me I had to calm down for him,
看護師さんが一
it really woke me up.
目が覚めました
I realized I had to be strong for him.
ああそうだって…この子 不安にさせてどうするんだって
Well...
そんな...
I'm glad the cuts weren't as deep as we thought.
でもよかったですね 思ったより傷も深くなくて
You did great, Takashi. Good job!
頑張ったね~貴史君偉いぞ!
Thank you so much.
本当にありがとうございました
I'm so glad we had the Number 1 glass-removing doctor in Japan
ガラスの破片を取らせたら 日本一の先生と
and a very nice nurse to take care of us.
優しい看護師さんがいてくれて よかったです
Excuse us.
失礼します
Take care.
お大事に
-Bye-bye.
(貴史)バイバーイ
Let's go.
帰ろっか
Ow.
痛つた… 甬つた
You must be happy.
よかったじゃねーか
Someone finally recognized your value as a nurse.
生まれて初めて 看護師として褒められて
What? That's not true.
なあによそれ そんなことないもん!
The Number 1 glass-removing doctor in Japan, huh?
俺なんか-
What an honor.
光栄だ な
But...
でも...
I'm happy, Naoki.
嬉しい入江君
Mothers are amazing.
お母さんってすごいよね
She carried Takashi all the way here.
貴史君抱えたまんまずっと ここまで走ってきたんだって
She's so tiny herself.
あんな小柄なのに
Yeah.
ああ
They're amazing.
すごいよねえ
The protective instinct of a mother is so powerful!
お母さんの子供守るパワーって なんかすっごいよね!
It sure is.
そうだな
Dr. Irie!
(看護師)入江先生!
I'm sorry. We have another patient.
すいませんまた患者さんが
What a crazy night.
ったくすげーな今夜は つに
Kotoko, go home. Another nurse is coming.
琴子お前もう帰れ もう一人応援が来るらしいから
Huh?
(RST)
Miss Yamamura is coming soon.
(看護師)そうね琴子さん じきに山村さんも来るはずだし やまむら
No, I can still work.
あ…いや大丈夫だよまだ
Naoki is still working. So, can I...
入江君頑張ってるのに 私だってまだ… こつ
What...?
(琴子)あれ..
This is weird... I can't stand...
変だな...足に力が…
-Kotoko! -Kotoko?
琴子!
Naoki...
(琴子)入江く...ん
She's awake!
あ! 目を覚ました!
It's true! Kotoko is awake!
本当だわ! 琴子ちゃん気がついたのね
Naoki! Kotoko is up!
お兄ちゃんお兄ちゃーん! 琴子ちゃんが!-
-Kotoko... -Mom, calm down.
琴子ちゃんが
What...? I...
あれ…私…
Kotoko, you collapsed at the hospital.
琴子ちゃん あなた病院で倒れたのよ
Naoki carried you home.
お兄ちゃんが病院から 運庣きたんだ
You've been sleeping until now.
それから今まで ずーっと寝ていたのよ
We were so worried! Thank God you're up.
心配したわあよかった! 気がついて…
I'm sorry I made you worry.
ごめんなさい 私心配かけちゃつて
That's right.
あいはらしげお (相原重雄)まったくだ
You really had us worried...
お前って奴は心配かけやがって
All is well! Kotoko's fine.
よかったよかった! つに あいちゃん...うん
I'm sorry, Kotoko!
(紀子)ごめんなさいね 琴子ちゃん!-
You caught our influenza!
私達のインフルエンザが うつったのよ~!
You had to work at the hospital
しかも病院も休めずに働いて
and take care of us as well.
私達の看病までして!
We pushed you too hard.
ごめんなさいね 無理させちゃつて
This is not it, Mom.
そんなことないですよ お義母さん
I slept well, so, I feel totally fine.
眠ったせいか もう全然平気ですし
If I take some medicine now, I'll be totally okay tomorrow.
今のうちに風邪薬飲んでおけば 明日にはもうケロリだと思います
Really, Kotoko?
本当?琴子ちゃん?
Yes! I'm fine!
はい!大丈夫大丈夫!
I'll bring you some water, then.
(紀子) ゃお水 持ってきてあげるわね じ
Thank you.
はいありがとうございます
Naoki! Look, Kotoko is up.
あっ…お兄ちゃん! ほら琴子ちゃんが
-Don't drink it. -What?
(直樹)飲むな
Not now.
まだ飲むな
but I'm totally fine now.
でももう全然平気だから.
I don't know why I totally blacked out--
あの時はなんか目の前が 真っ白になっちゃつて なつ C.
Kotoko.
(直樹)琴子
When...
お前...
...was your last period?
前の生理いつだった?
W-- W-- What...?
な...な...何 よ…な... ID
Why...do...you ask?
そんなそんな き…き…聞くの!?
What are you saying?
(紀子)そうよ!お兄ちゃん
Are you...?
お前...
...pregnant?
妊娠してないか?
Ready?
(琴子)せーの!
Jump!
ジャーンプ...
Naoki.
ねえ入江君
Nothing.
何でもない
Kotoko.
琴子